CHRIS ESQUERRA Software Developer

210-763-6803

esquerrac@gmail.com 💌

in/chris-esquerra/ in

A software developer with a background centered on multidisciplinary collaboration in the military healthcare industry. Through prioritizing the client experience, I aim to grow myself and those around me with focus squarely on the outcomes for both internal and external customers to develop the highest quality product possible on any given project.

DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Closetry Corner 11/2018

A full stack Java app developed with Spring Boot featuring tools for users to upload and sort garments by various categories as well as plan and save outfits.

Adlister Fever 10/2018

Full stack advertisement posting and sorting web app with geolocation and messaging features. Utilizes Java EE and MySQL to allow users to post, search, and sort through a relational database.

Math Practice 09/2018

Interactive game designed for preschoolers to practice their basic math skills with animations and adjustable difficulty.

EDUCATION

FullStack Web Development **Codeup**

San Antonio, TX 07/2018 - 11/2018 Immersive, project driven 18 week career

accelerator program with over 600 hours of expert instruction and keyboard time in software development.

BS Criminal Justice **Strayer University**

San Antonio, TX 10/2016 - 07/2018

Degree currently pending transition to CS

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML/CSS - Bootstrap - JavaScript - jQuery - Java - Java EE - Spring Boot - SQL training with MSSql Server, MySQL and JDBC - C# - Entity Framework

WORK EXPERIENCE

Associate Software Engineer **Social Solutions**

San Antonio, TX 12/2018 - Present Construct Software as a service programs for Non-Profit Organizations to increase service capacity and improve outcomes for clientele, as well as develop products to provide predictive analytics indicating best practices.

Healthcare Manager United States Air Force

San Antonio, TX 03/2013 - 05/2016

Managed family violence intervention services to over 60k beneficiaries. Supervised and ensured educational currency of 35 staff members at 3 geographic locations in accordance with federal and healthcare accreditation standards.

Health Education Specialist **United States Air Force**

Republic of Korea 02/2012 - 03/2013

Created and distributed mental health, addiction, and family violence prevention content to over 20 squadrons of military personnel via classes, theater presentations, and radio broadcasts.